Frank Duckart

2452 Tusitala Street, Apt. 1107 Honolulu, HI 96815

808-277-2190

email: duckart@computer.org
https://github.com/fduckart

https://www.linkedin.com/in/fduckart

Summary

Software developer with diverse experience, strong design skills, and enthusiasm for successful engineering processes.

Platforms: Comprehensive experience developing web applications on Linux and Solaris. Prior experience building desktop applications for MS Windows.

Quality: Best practices experience in a number of development methodologies. Experience using source control, including Subversion, Git, Perforce, and SourceSafe. Daily use of version/feature/bug tracking in JIRA. Long experience using build tools such as Maven and Ant, including their integration with various static code-checkers. Experience developing unit, integration, and system tests. Strong emphasis on using continuous integration and testing tools to aid in developing and deploying quality software.

Communication: Extensive background interacting with internal and external clients for requirements gathering, scheduling, development, and testing purposes. Excellent written English skills, including technical specifications and technical editing.

Experience

2008–Present University of Hawaii Honolulu, HI *Information Technology Specialist* (Senior Programmer)

Team member of the system-wide MIS group, developing and maintaining administrative web-based applications. Regular experience using Java, JUnit, Spring Framework, HTML, JSP, CSS, XML, Javascript, Linux, Solaris, Bash, SQL, Oracle, MySQL, and Hibernate ORM. Experienced in CAS integration for authentication, and LDAP integration for directory searches. Responsible for deploying applications to our Red Hat Enterprise Linux servers using various methods, including the use of the Jenkins continuous integration server.

2006–2008 Harvard Business School Publishing Boston, MA Senior Programmer Consultant
Application Development while living in Honolulu, HI. See below.

1999–2006 Harvard Business School Publishing Boston, MA Senior Programmer

Java/ATG developer for hbr.org, selling Harvard Business Review articles, Books, and Harvard Business School Cases: wrote and deployed major aspects of the system; designed and/or reviewed proposed architecture changes; created and updated automated data feeds and logic for back-end data transfers; wrote pages, Beans, Droplets, and Form Handlers for website; fixed bugs; analyzed and corrected

performance problems in Java code and SQL statements; created and modified KSH and BASH scripts. J2EE 1.3 &1.4, ATG 7.1, JHTML, JSP, KSH, Bash, Solaris, Oracle, SQL Server, ATG Dynamo, JUnit, Ant Responsible for all application development for Documentum document management system. Designed and developed numerous import and export programs. Designed and developed desktop and Intranet applications used for data-entry. J2SE 1.5, DQL, XML (e.g., Xerces, XOM), Visual Basic,C++, Junit Application Programmer for internal systems, responsible for development and/or maintenance on nearly all custom systems used by HBSP. Designed and developed applications for data-entry of publication titles, Art department job tracking, purchasing, inventory, tax reporting, data migration, bank data transfer, reporting, and numerous other applications. Also responsible for import and export programs used to transfer or migrate data from system to system. Visual C++, Visual Basic, J2SE 1.3-1.5, JBoss, JSP, HTML, ASP, HTML, Javascript.

Database design and development. Extensive experience developing and/or maintaining database systems. Created and/or enhanced database systems used by applications. Designed and developed tables, views, queries, stored-procedures, triggers. Oracle, SQL Server, Firefox, Access, MySQL, SQL, P/L SQL, T-SQL, Hibernate

1992–1999 Keane, Inc Boston, WA Programming Consultant for General Electric

Developed database applications using a variety of technologies. The applications, which provide solutions for a number of groups at a single client site, include an order entry and tracking system, a part specification entry and report system, supplier viability reporting intranet system, and a customer correspondence history system, and other database systems. Microsoft Visual Basic, C/C++, HTML, and Access, Oracle, and SQL Server, ODBC, VAX/ VMS.

Education

2003–2006 Boston University Boston, MA M.S., Computer Science

2000–2003 Boston University Boston, MA Undergraduate Certificate in Software Development

1988–1990 University of California, Santa Cruz Santa Cruz, CA B.S., Earth Sciences

Associations

Member of IEEE-CS and ACM